Robert Wagner

Taylorsville, UT | rob.wagnerusa@protonmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | 385.495.4015

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Dynamic Technical Writing Professional with a background in SaaS Support, Sales & Marketing, Banking, Communications, and Education. I look forward to bringing my Technical Writing skills, creativity, and experience to the team, and creating new content!

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

T1C – Salt Lake City, UT (Remote) | Director of Sales and Marketing (Interim)

June 2024 - Present

T1C provides emotional KPI solutions, unifying teams' collective capacities, engaging individuals, and improving both productivity, satisfaction, and tenure among employees.

- Created content for this month's email marketing campaign which resulted in a successful 35% open rate, and 4% conversion as I began processing leads.
- Run customer sales presentations, leveraging technical and marketing documentation, and enhancing customer knowledge of T1C's products and solutions.
- Tools | ZOHO CRM, Email Campaign, Snagit, Figma, Microsoft Suite, and ChatGPT Al.

MVi – Salt Lake City, UT | Applications Support Engineer & Technical Writer Nov 2017 – May 2024

MVi provides SaaS Solutions for Financial Institutions and Municipalities in Electronic Content Management systems, including hardware/software deployment and support.

- 1,000's of technical case notes and documents produced both in technical solutions,
 SaaS Software Support, Education and Marketing.
- Provided custom-designed documentation on how to deploy, use, and troubleshoot software and How-To's on leveraging key software features for customers.
- **Special Project** | Upgraded MVi's Annual Review Form from a fillable PDF to a user-friendly web form, improving efficiency, collaboration, and engagement for the entire org.
- Tools | Laserfiche Server, Client, Workflow, Forms, and Import Agent, Microsoft Suite, CRM, SQL Server, SSMS, HTML, XML, CSS, PHP, JS.

Robert Half – Lehi, UT | Recruiting Manager

Mar 2017 – Oct 2017

Robert Half provides talent sourcing services for Finance and Accounting roles, as well as Technical and other business process roles

- Sourced and presented qualified finance and accounting candidates within tight deadlines.
- Built a robust network, increasing talent pool by 800% in six months.
- Collaborated with teams to prioritize objectives and foster long-term client relationships.

Utah First Credit Union – Midvale, UT | Assistant Branch Manager *Jan 2016 - Feb 2017*

- Designed a branch-specific marketing slick, and used it to prospect local dealerships
- Added 3 new dealer partners to the branch the same week and began taking new applications
- Reduced branch turnover from 75% to 25% through team building and engagement practices.

Universal Technical Institute – Rancho Cucamonga, CA | Field Admissions Representative

Feb 2012 - Dec 2015

Universal Tech. provides technical career training for Automotive, Diesel, and motorsports industries.

- Expanded active accounts from 15 to 50+, generating \$800K-\$1.2M annually.
- Delivered career presentations and conducted extensive student interviews, supporting education and career planning.

BECU (Boeing Employees Credit Union) – Maple Valley, WA | Member Consultant Jan 2006 – Feb 2012

- Drove new membership through branch marketing campaigns and writing marketing content to drive store traffic to our in-store credit union location.
- Achieved top 10% performance (NET Promoter) in customer service out of a 1,400-person team, enhancing member satisfaction and credit union growth.
- Coordinated financial literacy programs, boosting youth membership applications.

Yellow Book, USA | Account Executive - Advertising

Oct 2004 – Dec 2005

- Drove \$200K+ in revenue through strategic sales and consulting customers on their local and Yellow Pages marketing campaigns.
- Assisted clients in achieving a 50% improvement in qualified conversions.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Science in Web Design & Development

BYU - Rexburg, Idaho

Certification in Snagit Screen Capture and Video Software

TechSmith – Online Training

Certification in Web Media

BYU - Rexburg, Idaho

Associate of Science in Arts/Business

Green River - Auburn, WA

ABOUT ME

My co-workers describe me as optimistic, fun, easy to work with, and creative. My strengths are communication, relationship building, and team collaboration, and hobbies include camping, hiking, basketball, and spending time with family.

Professional Recommendations available here.